In the last few videos we talked about how to do forward propagation and
在之前几个视频里，我们讨论了如何进行前向传播
back propagation in a neural network in order to compute derivatives.
以及后向传播，从而计算导数
But back prop as an algorithm has a lot of details and
但，后向传播有很多细节，
can be a little bit tricky to implement.
这些细节有点复杂
And one unfortunate property is that there are many ways to
有一个不幸的消息是，
have subtle bugs in back prop.
它们有很多细节会导致一些BUG
So that if you run it with gradient descent or
如果你用梯度下降来计算，
some other optimizational algorithm, it could actually look like it's working.
你会发现表面上它可以工作
And your cost function,
实际上，
J of theta may end up decreasing on every iteration of gradient descent.
J 虽然每次迭代都在下降
But this could prove true even though there might be some
但是可能，
bug in your implementation of back prop.
仍然你的代码有很多BUG
So that it looks J of theta is decreasing, but
所以，表面上关于theta的函数J在减小
you might just wind up with a neural network that has a higher level of
但是你可能最后得到的结果
error than you would with a bug free implementation.
实际上有很大的误差
And you might just not know that there was this subtle bug that was giving you
你这时候可能知道，有一些小的BUG导致
worse performance.
这种不好的算法性能表现
So, what can we do about this?
所以，怎么办呢
There's an idea called gradient checking
有一个想法叫梯度检验 Gradient Checking
that eliminates almost all of these problems.
它能减少这种错误的概率
So, today every time I implement back propagation or
就我个人而言，每次我使用后向传播
a similar gradient to a [INAUDIBLE] on a neural network or
我都会[]用这种方法
any other reasonably complex model, I always implement gradient checking.
即使是其他比较复杂的模型，我都会做这种检查
And if you do this, it will help you make sure and sort of gain high confidence that
如果你这么做，你会对你的模型更有自信
your implementation of four prop and back prop or whatever is 100% correct.
这样，你会更加确信的模型是100%正确的
And from what I've seen this pretty much eliminates all the problems associated
从我看到的情况，这种方法，
with a sort of a buggy implementation as a back prop.
很大程度可以减少错误的可能性
And in the previous videos I asked you to take on faith that the formulas I gave for
在之前的视频里，我让你们相信
computing the deltas and the vs and so on, I asked you to take on
我给你们的公式是正确的，
faith that those actually do compute the gradients of the cost function.
我还让你们相信，这就是支付函数的梯度值
But once you implement numerical gradient checking, which is the topic of this
但，一旦你使用梯度检验，
video, you'll be able to absolute verify for yourself that the code you're writing
也就是我们这个视频的主题，你会证明你的代码
does indeed, is indeed computing the derivative of the cross function J.
实际上就是梯度函数
So here's the idea, consider the following example.
所以，这就是我们的想法，来看一个例子
Suppose that I have the function J of theta and I have some value theta
假设我们有一个关于theta的函数H
and for this example gonna assume that theta is just a real number.
我现在有它的一个值，假设是实数
And let's say that I want to estimate the derivative of this function at this point
我们说，我想要预测它的倒数，
and so the derivative is equal to the slope of that tangent one.
所以倒数是等于这里的斜度
Here's how I'm going to numerically approximate the derivative, or
现在我用这种方法来接近，
rather here's a procedure for numerically approximating the derivative.
我们不采用数值的计算倒数，
I'm going to compute theta plus epsilon, so now we move it to the right.
这里我用epsilon，
And I'm gonna compute theta minus epsilon and I'm going to look at those two
同样也有一个减去epsilon的值
points, And connect them by a straight line
然后把他们链接起来
And I'm gonna connect these two points by a straight line, and I'm gonna use
我将得到一条直线
the slope of that little red line as my approximation to the derivative.
我用这个红色线来近似我的导数
Which is, the true derivative is the slope of that blue line over there.
恩，真正的斜率是蓝色的线。
So, you know it seems like it would be a pretty good approximation.
所以，你可以看到这是一个很好的近似。
Mathematically, the slope of this red line is this vertical height
数学上，这里的红线垂直高度
divided by this horizontal width.
除以这个水平宽度，就是我们的斜率
So this point on top is the J of (Theta plus Epsilon).
所以，这个点，就是J()
This point here is J (Theta minus Epsilon), so
这个点，(theta减掉epsilon)
this vertical difference is J (Theta plus Epsilon) minus J
我们有一个垂直的差值()减去
of theta minus epsilon and this horizontal distance is just 2 epsilon.
这两个点的差值，以及水平宽度2epsilon
So my approximation is going to be that the derivative
所以我们可以近似来表示
respect of theta of J of theta at this value of theta, that that's approximately
这是近似的值，
J of theta plus epsilon minus J of theta minus epsilon over 2 epsilon.
它等于J加上epsilon减去J减去epsilon对应的函数值，除以2倍的epsilon
Usually, I use a pretty small value for
通常，
epsilon, expect epsilon to be maybe on the order of 10 to the minus 4.
这个epsilon非常小，可能就是10的-4次方
There's usually a large range of different values for epsilon that work just fine.
而误差值往往很大，
And in fact, if you let epsilon become really small, then mathematically
所以近似效果很好。实际上
this term here, actually mathematically, it becomes the derivative.
如果让epsilon无穷小，这就是导数的定义
It becomes exactly the slope of the function at this point.
恩，它就是导数。
It's just that we don't want to use epsilon that's too,
所以，
too small, because then you might run into numerical problems.
但我们不希望epsilon太小，否则会有计算上的问题
So I usually use epsilon around ten to the minus four.
一般来说在10的-4次方比较合适
And by the way some of you may have seen an alternative formula for
通常，你可能见到这个类似的公式
s meeting the derivative which is this formula.
恩。
This one on the right is called a one-sided difference,
所以，右边的叫做单边导数
whereas the formula on the left, that's called a two-sided difference.
左边的叫做双边导数
The two sided difference gives us a slightly more accurate estimate, so
后者的精确度更高，
I usually use that, rather than this one sided difference estimate.
当然，一般我们用后者
So, concretely, when you implement an octave, is you implemented the following,
所以，具体来说，当你用octave，
you implement call to compute gradApprox,
你计算近似梯度时候，
which is going to be our approximation derivative as just here this formula,
我们用的是这个公式。
J of theta plus epsilon minus J of theta minus epsilon divided by 2 times epsilon.
恩。。就是红色标注的双边导数近似公式，除以的是2倍
And this will give you a numerical estimate of the gradient at that point.
所以，我们有一个近似的值
And in this example it seems like it's a pretty good estimate.
在这个例子，它看起来非常好地近似我们的结果
Now on the previous slide,
在之前的PPT里
we considered the case of when theta was a rolled number.
我们考虑了theta是一个向量
Now let's look at a more general case of when theta is a vector parameter, so
现在，我们来看一般的情况
let's say theta is an R n.
我们说theta是一个矩阵
And it might be an unrolled version of the parameters of our neural network.
我们有一个舒展的参数版本，
So theta is a vector that has n elements, theta 1 up to theta n.
所以，这里theta是从1到n的向量
We can then
我们，
use a similar idea to approximate all the partial derivative terms.
可以用近似的方式来进行计算
Concretely the partial derivative of a cost function with respect to the first
可以看到，我们列出各个近似的求导公式
parameter, theta one, that can be obtained by taking J and increasing theta one.
theta 1套前面的公式是这样，
So you have J of theta one plus epsilon and so on.
如此种种。
Minus J of this theta one minus epsilon and divide it by two epsilon.
恩。。
The partial derivative respect to the second parameter theta two, is again this
这里都是偏导数。
thing except that you would take J of here you're increasing theta two by epsilon,
只改变theta 1的值，其他的值固定
and here you're decreasing theta two by epsilon and so on down to the derivative.
分母一样，还是2 epsilon
With respect of theta n would give you increase and decrease theta and
我们现在可以得到我们想要的近似结果
by epsilon over there.
恩，
So, these equations give you a way to numerically approximate the partial
所以这个公式组给出了近似的方法
derivative of J with respect to any one of your parameters theta i.
对于任意一个theta我们都有
Completely, what you implement is therefore the following.
完整地，你可以这样应用。
We implement the following in octave to numerically compute the derivatives.
我们用octave来数值计算，
We say, for
比如，
i = 1:n, where n is the dimension of our parameter of vector theta.
对于i=1:n，其中n是我们参数的个数
And I usually do this with the unrolled version of the parameter.
一般我们习惯是舒展的向量而不是矩阵
So theta is just a long list of all of my parameters in my neural network, say.
所以theta是长长的参数清单
I'm gonna set thetaPlus = theta,
这里设置thetaPlus = theta
then increase thetaPlus of the (i) element by epsilon.
之后增加(i)项epsilon
And so this is basically thetaPlus is equal to theta except for
恩，这就等于我们
thetaPlus(i) which is now incremented by epsilon.
thetaPlus(i)，
Epsilon, so theta plus is equal to, write theta 1, theta 2 and so on.
theta1, theta2如此种种
Then theta I has epsilon added to it and then we go down to theta N.
thetal ，一直到N
So this is what theta plus is.
所以，这是thetaPlus的含义
And similar these two lines set theta minus to something similar except
类似的
that this instead of theta I plus Epsilon, this now becomes theta I minus Epsilon.
我们现在也有l 减去epsilon
And then finally you implement this gradApprox (i) and
最后你会使用这个gradApprox(i)
this would give you your approximation to the partial derivative
并且能够给你一个偏微分单数
respect of theta i of J of theta.
对于i
And the way we use this in our neural network implementation is,
这就是我们使用的方法
we would implement this four loop to compute the top partial derivative
我们可以用一个循环来写
of the cost function for respect to every parameter in that network, and
来检验这个近似计算的结果是不是等于我们的计算结果
we can then take the gradient that we got from backprop.
也就是反向传播算法计算的梯度
So DVec was the derivative we got from backprop.
Dvec就是我们得到的导数
All right, so backprop, backpropogation,
好的，
was a relatively efficient way to compute a derivative or a partial derivative.
反向传播是一个非常高效的算法，
Of a cost function with respect to all our parameters.
针对所有的参数
And what I usually do is then, take my numerically computed derivative
我们通常做的是数值计算的结果
that is this gradApprox that we just had from up here.
也就是刚才所做的
And make sure that that is equal or approximately equal up to
确信这是相等的，
small values of numerical round up, that it's pretty close.
应该说非常接近
So the DVec that I got from backprop.
所以DVec，我们从反向传播得到，
And if these two ways of computing the derivative give me the same answer, or
如果得到同一个结果
give me any similar answers, up to a few decimal places,
或者相近的结果，只相差一些小数位
then I'm much more confident that my implementation of backprop is correct.
我们很确信这个反向传播的算法是正确的
And when I plug these DVec vectors into gradient assent or
如果我代入梯度计算
some advanced optimization algorithm, I can then be much more
一些高级的算法
confident that I'm computing the derivatives correctly, and therefore that
我们会更加确信我们的导数计算是正确的
hopefully my code will run correctly and do a good job optimizing J of theta.
因此，我们的代码不仅正确，而且在优化上性能很好
Finally, I wanna put everything together and
最后，我想总结一下
tell you how to implement this numerical gradient checking.
告诉你梯度检验的相关内容
Here's what I usually do.
这是我通常做的事情
First thing I do is implement back propagation to compute DVec.
首先，使用反向传播来计算，它是很好的算法
So there's a procedure we talked about in the earlier video
这里就是前面介绍的流程
to compute DVec which may be our unrolled version of these matrices.
这里的参数我们把矩阵展开成向量
So then what I do,
然后
is implement a numerical gradient checking to compute gradApprox.
我们使用数值的梯度来检验
So this is what I described earlier in this video and in the previous slide.
这是刚刚介绍的内容
Then should make sure that DVec and gradApprox give similar values,
我们要确信这两个方法算出来结果一致
you know let's say up to a few decimal places.
你知道，就差一点
And finally and this is the important step, before you start to use your
最后，也是最重要的步骤
code for learning, for seriously training your network, it's important to turn
就是在你开始学习之前，
off gradient checking and to no longer compute this gradApprox thing using
一定要关掉我们的梯度检验，
the numerical derivative formulas that we talked about earlier in this video.
也就是我们讨论的数值计算方法
And the reason for that is the numeric code gradient checking code,
原因是这个计算过程，
the stuff we talked about in this video, that's a very computationally expensive,
实际上代价更高，复杂度也很高
that's a very slow way to try to approximate the derivative.
这不是一个很好的计算导数的方法
Whereas In contrast, the back propagation algorithm that we talked about earlier,
相反，我们前面讨论的反向传播算法
that is the thing we talked about earlier for computing.
很早以前介绍的内容
You know, D1, D2, D3 for Dvec.
你知道D1 D2 D3对于DVEC
Backprop is much more computationally efficient way of computing for
相对来说非常高效。
derivatives.
恩
So once you've verified that your implementation of back propagation is
所以，一旦你检验证明你的算法没有错误
correct, you should turn off gradient checking and just stop using that.
就要把梯度检验关掉
So just to reiterate, you should be sure to disable your gradient checking code
所以，你一定要关掉
before running your algorithm for many iterations of gradient descent or for
在你开始迭代训练之前
many iterations of the advanced optimization algorithms,
对于其他很多优化算法也一样
in order to train your classifier.
为了训练你的分类器
Concretely, if you were to run the numerical gradient checking on
具体来说，如果你一定要用数值方法
every single iteration of gradient descent.
来计算梯度，
Or if you were in the inner loop of your costFunction,
那么你的算法会非常慢。
then your code would be very slow.
在你的支付函数的循环过程当中
Because the numerical gradient checking code is much slower
因为，正如前面所说
than the backpropagation algorithm, than the backpropagation method where,
我们再重复一下...它很慢
you remember, we were computing delta(4), delta(3), delta(2), and so on.
记得，我们这里计算(4)(3)(2)等等
That was the backpropagation algorithm.
这是我们的反向传播算法
That is a much faster way to compute derivates than gradient checking.
它快得多
So when you're ready, once you've verified the implementation of back propagation is
所以，再说一遍...检验完了后向传播没有问题
correct, make sure you turn off or you disable your gradient checking code
关掉梯度检验，重要的事情说三遍
while you train your algorithm, or else you code could run very slowly.
当你在训练你的算法的时候，
So, that's how you take gradients numericaly, and that's how you can verify
所以数值的计算，
tha implementation of back propagation is correct.
这是你的检验方法而已。
Whenever I implement back propagation or similar gradient discerning algorithm for
对我而言，每当我要使用梯度算法，比如后向传播
a complicated mode,l I always use gradient checking and
我都会用梯度检验一下这个算法是否正确
this really helps me make sure that my code is correct.
这会让我更加自信我的算法是正确的。